all right guys in this video I'm going
to show you guys a comb over and why we
have to cut each side differently on
this side we're going to part the hair
down and this way and we're going to
comb all the hair over here to here and
I'm going to show you how obviously how
to make it look symmetrical even though
they're both going to be cut different
I'm also going to show you guys the
difference between a taper comb which is
a smaller comb a midsize comb white comb
and a flat larger comb red comb and
there really is a small difference it
kind of just goes to whatever you choose
but I'll show you guys in the video it's
going to be a full haircut it's going to
be the first full haircut on my YouTube
channel and we're doing it with some
teapop clippers let's get it all right
so the very first step of every haircut
that I do especially if it's a new
client is always calm the hair down you
never know what you're dealing
with so I'm just combing his hair making
sure everything's good I'm going to do
the same thing on the other side I'm
doing here and the reason why I don't
record full haircuts is because I have
to keep switching the camera angle and
it just takes too much time
but because I love the support you guys
give me I'mma do it and I hope you guys
like this video and this type of content
and if you do I never say this but drop
a like and drop a subscribe thank you so
now that we're done combing the hair the
only thing that I see is over here
towards the back area where his
occipital bonees sat he has like a a
major bump and it shows in his head if I
show him over here you kind of see it
right so when I come down down to this
area I'm going to try my best to drop it
down below that so we can keep keep this
side heavy to hide that whether he likes
it or not it Just will look better if he
has more hair here so whatever type of
fade he gives me I automatically know it
doesn't matter if he has me for a high
fade a mid fade or a low fade I'm going
to drop it down here no matter what
we're going to make our zero gu line
right
here and like I said we're dropping it
down in the back so I'm going to make a
line
here and I want to give myself enough
room to blend so look down a little bit
so we see this is the part we're trying
to get so I want to give myself a good
amount to blend so instead of making my
zero guideline all the way down here or
up here and not giving myself this much
room to blend I'm actually going to do
it drop it a little bit lower worst case
scenario we have to go a little bit
higher no big deal but if we go too high
we can't go lower so that's the idea
with starting low
yeah B all right so obviously you can
see that this line is not straight it's
not perfect by any means and I just want
to show you guys I want to show you guys
that no matter what it's okay to not
spend too much time and to not have the
initial guideline perfect now that I
balded everything underneath I'm going
to go and I'm going to make sure that
it's symmetrical both sides so I'm going
to come over here I'm just going to
retouch it up I'm going to flick out as
I get to that line to make a soft
guideline the softer the guideline the
easier it is going to be to blend so
we're going to see take a real good look
back here if you see it it looks all
wobbly here right so all we're trying to
do here now is trying to make it look
symmetrical
so so obviously we can see that this
side is higher than this side all I'm
going to do is not touch the right side
go a little bit higher on the left side
and it doesn't have to be insanely
symmetrical but that's it the whole
point is not to spend too much time on
this
cool now that we have our first we're
going to start balding out and I've been
using these Shavers cuz I absolutely
love them they're strong they're small
and like you can damn near put this
anywhere anywhere so as you can see I'm
leaving myself about a room here right
and then once I get to like this area
right here I'm going to start flicking
out so the shaver can blend straight
into the zero line you're going to see
it over and over again that I'm just
going going to flick
out as I get there right here I'm
flicking out you can even see these
hairs moving cuz I'm actually flicking
out
right now we're going to do the same
thing here as we close to this line
right here we're going to flick
out same thing
here and right here we're going to get
these little hairs behind the
ear and that's it
this next step is going to be the same
we're going to go with the lever all the
way
open and we're just going
to go about a comb
sth a small comb
sth and if you're a beginner I always
say give yourself enough room to blend
here there's absolutely no reason for
you to be making small guidelines if
you're making small guidelines you're
literally making your life harder you're
making your life harder that means
you're going to give yourself you're not
going to give yourself the confidence to
cut and if you don't have confidence
it's not going to be fun if it's not fun
you're going to hate it and if you hate
it you're going to be
bad our two main objectives for this
haircut is to keep this dark that way we
have support here for the hair to comb
down because he wants to comb this down
he doesn't want this short and our
second objective is to keep this dark to
hide that little thing right there that
he has so that little bump so because we
want to keep it dark we're going to use
our dark guard which is a three okay I
need you guys to think think of guards
as Shades and the darker you get up here
the better the blend's going to get so
we're going to use a three guard which
is a dark guard you can with the lever
all the way open and we're going to go
all the way up there and we're going to
follow that same shape as the other two
lines and if you make a line it's okay
all
right it's preferable if you don't make
a line and you do that by flicking out
and it's not scooping it you're not
scooping everyone talks about a scooping
motion that's completely wrong it's
really wrong all you really got to do is
angle your Clipper out a little bit and
just go straight up that's all you got
to
do and obviously you keep it angled you
don't go back you just keep it angled
and you go up up up
up as we're getting over here to this
area obviously we're keeping the same
amount here as we are here as we are
over here whatever guard I put here on
the Ridge area or on the Ridge area
right I like going with it downwards if
it looks a little too bulky
that one didn't cut anything and over
here we're doing so far it's the same
thing on both sides
okay now that we have our top done you
can see it's blending nicely into the
top but we're still going to blend it a
little better you can see a little bit
of bulk here a little bit of bulk there
now we're going to go back down to our
zero guard right and all we're going to
do here is this is with the lever all
the way open which is open now we're
going to close the two notches down
we're going to go right in between both
of these lines and and that's all we're
doing right now that's all we're
focusing
on now we're going to and you can see I
only passed it one time and that just
goes to show that you don't have to keep
going at it you can if you want to just
don't take too much time on it don't
spend too much time on
it now we're going to close our lever
all the way down one two and we're going
to get rid of that zero
[Music]
line
[__] now we left a small little zero
line and I'm going to take some clippers
that I have that are not zero Gap and
these are my PL Clippers so I'm just
going to go right at that zero line I'm
just going to barely touch
it just to make sure I don't if I go too
high up it's not a big deal because
they're not fully zero Gap so they
shouldn't leave like a a big line but if
you can't still take that zero line out
then whatever you made that line withd
you can take it out you can take it out
with that same guard and as you can see
the zero line was pretty cuz my other
clip are super zero Gap and this that's
the struggle of having really zero Gap
Clippers sometimes the good thing is
that they Maul through the hair like
they're going to cut the hair ASAP and
they're going to cut it crispy the bad
thing is that sometimes you leave a
little line but you see we fixed it we
we fixed it no big deal okay so we're
using the three guard method today our
first guard was the number three guard
now our second guard is the 1 and a half
guard the one and a half guard as long
as we angle it out properly and we go up
it's going to blend right into the three
guard now we know we put put our three
guard all the way up here so obviously
we're not going to put our 1 and 1/2
guard all the way up there because if we
do then we're going to make a line and
obviously this does not cut hair so if
we put it all the way up there it's not
going to do anything right this is not
going to cut it what what cuts is the
cutting blade all the way down here this
is a guiding guard the second blade that
you see up here is a guiding blade and
this little one that you see back there
that's actual cutting blade so we're
going to go up here we're going to angle
it out a little bit go straight
up so I forgot to mention that we have
the guard all the way open right now and
keep in mind we don't want to go way too
high up here so we're going to go right
underneath that
bone but we also don't want to go too
little because then we're going to
create a lot of
bulk so as you guys can see here with
our three guard we didn't blend it in
properly but that's not a big deal we're
going to take care of
that the last card we're going to use
and we're almost done with the blending
process the only lines that we have to
take care of are this line right here
and this soft line up here and that's it
we're done with the haircut okay it's
that simple we have a system we did our
zero we balded it out we did our half
line we know how to take care of our
zero line right then we did our three
our 1 and A2 and now we're doing our
half and that's it so what are we doing
with this card we're going with the
lever all the way open and we're going
to do the same thing instead of having
the blade flat on this head we're going
to angle it out a little bit which means
most of the what's going to be touching
his head is this area right here it's
not this area this area is not going to
touch a set at all if this area is
touching a set that's going to cause
digging if this area is touching a set
it's going to promote the right angle
and all you have to go do is go up and
down with it right now obviously this is
too much this is not going to cut hair
so it's got to be slight this is digging
in this is how you want it so when you
go up there you can see that this line
is getting lighter and lighter and we're
applying very light pressure here a lot
of people go like this on the client's
head and like they're very rough it's
not about being rough it's about being
nice and light and when you're nice and
light it's kind of like if you're tra
ing like if you're shading very light on
a piece of paper right and you know
exactly how much pressure to put on that
pencil to make sure that it's like a
nice light gray it's the same idea it's
very light very I don't know how to say
it I guess just light no
pressure okay and we kept the lever open
and it's practically blended it it
doesn't always work out that way
hopefully it works out that way over
here and and and on the other side but
sometimes if the line is still there
like right here EX for example you just
close the two notches down so one two
and then you hit it
again and that should get rid of the
line and sometimes that doesn't work out
you go one two and then you do it again
but you can see a nice smooth blend now
on this side all we have to take care of
is that line and we're done with this
side let's keep going with the other
side so same thing we have our lever all
the way open very light
pressure we have the angle we have the
Clipper angled out over here his hair is
growing sideways so we're going to go
against the
grain and I'm only doing with this
corner this corner is elevated
right and we're doing it because his
hair is growing it over here if we go
like this we're not going to cut
anything
all right so we got muscle head over
here and because he has a lot of like
meat here and muscle it's very hard to
blend you can see when he smiles all of
this is very very compressed right and
that makes it really hard to blend and
it sounds like a joke but I'm not joking
you'll get a lot of people like this I
have a head like this too right so what
do you do here all you got to do is put
the ear down and just stretch the skin
so like I said on the other side it
doesn't always work out in the in the
first go right here we have all my
Clipper all the way open and it's not
blending in properly so what I'm going
going to do close the two notches go to
the same
spot if that doesn't work I'm going
close the two more notches and go to the
same
spot and now you can see that this side
was a little bit more hard but it's
starting to blend in properly now and
guess what it still looks a little dark
there so we're just going to go up there
all the way open the higher you go the
more you want to open your lever the
lower you go the more you want to close
the
lever so you can see how dark it is over
here all I'm trying to do is lighten it
cuz it goes from light to dark too quick
there's not a smooth transition
there all right we're almost done with
this side then we got to do the back and
we got to blend the top and that's
it all right this line I can still see a
little bit so I'm going to take my
Clipper off
off and close the two notches and go
right at that line all we're worried
about right here is this line and it's
super heavy super dark so this is all
the way open and I'm going all the way
up
here and now halfway two notches
down and now all the way close
so now the only thing we have to take
care of is this line but before we take
care of it we got to understand what
makes this line right well what makes
this line is that these hairs up here
are short and these hairs all the way up
here these that I'm touching are long
and they all come over here and they
create bulk the other thing that I want
you guys to
understand is the shape that that you're
looking at right so when I take this
line out you're going to see that the
hair is not going like this it's
actually going to go like this right and
that's what creates that bulk and in
order to create a smooth fade you need a
straight line like this so once I take
this hair
out we're going to go up here and I'm
going to get it from the angle and sure
enough look at that line is exactly what
I was looking at what I said it was
going to be see how it's really long up
here right so I'm going get one single
Strand and you can
see that it going it's going straight
straight straight straight and then it
droops out so straight straight straight
straight and then it droops out up here
and so what do we got to do all we got
to do is take care of those hairs that
droop out now that we understand that's
what it looks like that's all the hairs
we're looking to cut and everything's
going to blend in smooth we saw the
hairs that I need to cut I'm going to
show you three different ways of cutting
it one small comb thin shoes we're going
to go up here keep your eyes
here now obviously if you do it once
you're going to leave it uneven the
whole point of this is not to do it once
you want to go up and you want to keep
doing it up until it Blends you can
still see it's heavy so I'm going to
keep
going and now you can see it's blending
in properly
right okay now it's lot smoother these
hairs we're going to end up cutting with
shears that's one way to do it second
way of doing it is a medium comb with
shears and it's the exact same thing the
only difference is with thinning shears
you're going to cut essentially every
other hair right with this you're going
to cut every single hair that you see up
here so you have to snip it less amount
of times The Reason Why th shars are so
essential is because if you make a wrong
snip it's okay it doesn't matter right
you have to keep doing it over and over
and over and over and over and over for
it cut it with these shears you only cut
it once and all that hair is gone so
we're going to go up here we're going to
be very
careful right and you see it's it took
one or two Snips for it to blend in
properly we're going to go up
here and everything's blending out a lot
smooth so that's the difference between
thinning shears and regular shears
thinning shears that's why I always say
they're better for beginners because if
you make the wrong snip it's okay no big
deal but if you make the wrong snip with
these it is is a big deal so use sing
shears the comb that you use does not
matter everyone wants to teach other
people about hey use this comb use that
it doesn't matter use whatever comb you
feel
comfortable last way of blending we're
going to use a flat comb and I like
using red Combs I don't like using black
Combs because black Combs you can't see
the hair and just your regular shears
your
regular
Clipper and really it's all about
understanding the angle that you have to
put your combing it's not about what
Clipper you use it's not about what what
tool you use it's all about
understanding this this and that angle
that you're trying to make so if I put
my comb like
this you're going to see that it creates
a straight line and as I
go I'm going to turn them you're going
to see that we're creating that shape
that I'm always talking
about I hope you guys can see it like
that you we're creating that shape that
I'm always talking about where it's an
upside triangle it's coming out as we go
up so I'm going to go up here
again right and you see how my comb is
touching here and as we get up there
it's coming out and you see how all the
hairs are going like that so if I go
like this I'm very confident that none
of these hairs are going to cut cuz it's
cut perfectly look at that and now we
look here look how smooth that blend
looks so it's all about creating that
right shape right and now remember how
we got all the hair remember remember
how we got all the hair over here and it
was sticking out and it was drooping out
it's not going to do that anymore so if
I grab my
comb and I go like this and I get the
comb out look back then or literally 5
minutes ago you will see a bunch of hair
sticking out here now you don't see that
anymore because it's Blended in properly
right if I go over here same thing it's
Blended in properly as we go up it's
slanting out all right bro and
now see how smooth that blends same
thing with this side this side is almost
Blended in properly already right so I'm
just going to do it with my comb really
quick and like I with my Clipper really
quick and like I said it doesn't matter
what Clipper you use what tool you use
as long as you understand the proper
angle it's fine don't let anyone tell
you hey you have to use this comb hey
you have to use shears hey you have to
use Clipper over comb you don't have to
okay and if anybody tells you that's not
true you could blame it on me and I've
been cutting here for 9 years and
obviously I understand how to cut hair I
know how to cut hair and I'm telling you
take it from me please take it from me
use whatever you feel comfortable with I
see people that cut with big ass shears
from here to here and that's how they
like doing it I see people
that that use their that one way too
loud I see people that literally use
their trimmers they'll literally go and
they'll use their trimmers like this and
if you want to you could do it if that
works for where you do it it's fine
that's it we're done with the haircut
that's how you do a smooth blend you can
see that right here in the back we
Blended in very properly he still has a
little wave back here but that's not and
we can't do anything about that but we
hit it by keeping it dark up here and
look how smooth that looks look at that
blend it literally looks perfect the
hair over here looks perfect when he
Combs it he's not going to have a line
and we blended it three different ways
and that is the power of knowing
understanding
what you need to do and then actually
doing it that looks
fire straight
up and that's no enhancements no nothing
that's just straight rod rod dogging
it the only thing I see is over
[Music]
here and we didn't even detail for this
haircut but now that we did our steps so
quick we have all the Time in the World
to detail if you want to be picky about
there being a little dark spot here you
could be picky if you want to be picky
about blending it like 100% perfectly
over here you can be picky if you want
to Bald it out you can be picky because
we did our steps fast you can do
whatever the [__] you want to do now all
right emotional Dage exactly